Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Print Matter, 1811-circa 2010; 213348; 22.19 Linear feet
  - Subseries VI.A. Hort Periodicals, 1900-1998; 205240; 9.08 Linear feet
    - Year Book of the Horticultural Society of New York, 1935-38 (bound), 1935 January-1939 January; 205252 (Offsite-box 92, Volume HSNY-9)
    - Year Book of the Horticultural Society of New York, 1935-38 (copy 2) (bound), 1935 January-1939 January; 205253 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-10)
    - Year Book of the Horticultural Society of New York, 1939-41 (bound), 1939 January-1941 January; 205254 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-11)
    - Year Book of the Horticultural Society of New York, 1939-41 (bound) (copy 2), 1939 January-1941 January; 205255 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-12)
    - Year Book of the Horticultural Society of New York (loose) (3 folders), 1930-1937, 1950; 205256 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 1-3)
      Includes original standalone copies of six Year Books, for years 1930, 1932, 1935, 1936, 1937, and 1950. There are four copies of the 1950 HSNY 50th anniversary year book (the cover of which is dated for its publication year of 1951).
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1930-32 (bound), 1930 January-1932 December; 205257 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-13)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1930-32 (copy 2) (bound), 205258 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-14)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1930-31 (loose), 1930 April-1931 December; 205294 (Offsite-box 102, Box P-3, Folder 1)
      Includes original standalone copies of some Bulletins for these years.
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1933-34 (bound), 1933 January-1934 December; 205259 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-15)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1933-34 (copy 2) (bound), 1933 January-1934 December; 205260 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-16)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1935-36 (bound), 1935 January-1936 December; 205265 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-17)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1935-36 (copy 2) (bound), 1935 January-1936 December; 205266 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-18)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1937-38 (bound), 1937 January-1938 December; 205269 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-19)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1937-38 (copy 2) (bound), 1937 January-1938 December; 205270 (Offsite-box 93, Volume HSNY-20)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1939-40 (bound), 1939 January-1940 December; 205271 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-21)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1939-40 (copy 2) (bound), 1939 January-1940 December; 205272 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-22)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1941-42 (bound), 1941 January-1942 December; 205273 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-23)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1941-42 (copy 2) (bound), 1941 January-1942 December; 205274 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-24)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1943-44 (bound), 1943 January-1944 December; 205285 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-25)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1943-44 (copy 2) (bound), 1943 January-1944 December; 205286 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-26)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1945-46 (bound), 1945 January-1946 December; 205288 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-27)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1945-46 (copy 2) (bound), 1945 January-1946 December; 205289 (Offsite-box 94, Volume HSNY-28)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1947-48 (bound), 1947 January-1948; 205290 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-29)
      The Monthly Bulletin ceases at October 1947, replaced by a Bulletin produced quarterly beginning in 1948.
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1947-48 (copy 2) (bound), 1947 January-1948; 205291 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-30)
    - Monthly Bulletin (loose) (3 folders), 1934-1937; 212849 (Offsite-box 102, Box P-3, Folder 2-4)
      Includes incomplete sets of unbound Monthly Bulletins.
    - Monthly Bulletin (loose) (3 folders), 1938-1941, 1946; 212851 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-4, Folder 1-3)
    - Bulletin, 1949-50 (bound), 1949-1950; 205292 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-31)
      The final Bulletin was published for first quarter 1950.
    - Bulletin, 1949-50 (copy 2) (bound), 1949-1950; 205293 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-32)
    - News,1951-52 (bound), 1951-1952; 205299 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-33)
    - News,1951-52 (copy 2) (bound), 1951-1952; 205300 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-34)
    - News,1953-54 (bound), 1953-1954; 205302 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-35)
    - News,1953-54 (copy 2) (bound), 1953-1954; 205312 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-36)
    - News,1955-56 (bound), 1955-1956; 205313 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-37)
    - News,1955-56 (copy 2) (bound), 1955-1956; 205314 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-38)
    - News (loose), 1951-1957; 205318 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 4)
      Includes original standalone copies of some News for these years.
    - Bulletin, 1957-59 (bound), 1957-1959; 205316 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-39)
      The first number of 1957 is still called News. The title Bulletin returns in July 1957.
    - Bulletin, 1957-59 (copy 2) (bound), 1957-1959; 205317 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-40)
    - Bulletin, 1957-59 (loose) (2 folders), 1957-1959; 205327 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-5, Folder 1-2)
    - Bulletin, 1960-61 (bound), 1960-1961; 205325 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-41)
    - Bulletin, 1960-61 (loose) (2 folders), 1960-1961; 205328 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-5, Folder 3-4)
    - Bulletin, 1962-63 (bound), 205326 (Offsite-box 95, Volume HSNY-42)
    - Bulletin, 1962 (loose), 205329 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-5, Folder 5)
    - Index to Bulletin, 1958-1962, 212863 (Offsite-box 104, Box P-8, Cards -)
    - Bulletin, 1963-1966 (loose) (4 folders), 1964-1966; 205331 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-6, Folder 1-4)
    - News (loose), 1963 November-1965 March; 205330 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-6, Folder 5)
      Includes reminders of events and other messages spun off into a separate document, formerly included in the Bulletin.
    - Bulletin, 1958-1961 (loose, additional copies) (3 folders), 205332 (Offsite-box 103, Box P-6, Folder 6-8)
    - Bulletin, 1962-1966 (loose, additional copies) (6 folders), 205333 (Offsite-box 104, Box P-7, Folder 1-6)
    - Bulletin, 1967-69 (bound), 1967-1969 January; 205335 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-43)
    - Bulletin, 1967-69 (loose, 2 copies) (6 folders), 1967-1969 Summer; 205336 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 4-9)
    - Bulletin, 1970-73 (loose, 3 copies) (3 folders), 1970-1973; 205337 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 10-12)
    - Member Newsletter, 1969-1983. (loose, 2 copies) (2 folders), 1969-1983 May; 212879 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 13-14)
    - Newsletter, 1983-98 (loose, 3 copies) (5 folders), 1983 June-1998 Fall; 205338 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 15-19)
    - Garden Magazine. List of Articles, 1979-1983, 1984; 205339 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 20)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1977 November-1978; 205340 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-44)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1978; 205341 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-45)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1979; 205342 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-46)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1979; 205343 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-47)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1980; 205344 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-48)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1980; 205345 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-49)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1981; 205346 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-50)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1981; 205353 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-51)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1982; 205347 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-52)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1983; 205348 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-53)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1983; 205349 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-54)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1984; 205350 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-55)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1984; 205351 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-56)
    - Garden Magazine (loose), 1980-1983, 1986; 212881 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 21)
  - Subseries VI.B. Other Hort Print Matter, 1901-circa 2010; 212898; 5.85 Linear feet
    The subseries is arranged roughly by the following document types, which are used as headings in the container list: manuscripts and publications; program brochures & pamphlets; forms, invitations & other ephemera; press & publicity; and posters & proclamations.
    The subseries includes a broad range of printed matter, especially ephemera, produced by the Hort over the course of the twentieth century and into the first decade of the twentieth first century. These include informational brochures and booklets, program calendars (ranging from 1933-2006), stationery and forms, membership solicitations, event announcements, admission tickets, press releases, posters, mayoral proclamations, and other documents. Many of these documents date from Hort's earliest years through the 1940s and were found in two (now disbound) scrapbooks. International Flower Shows, New York Flower Shows, lectures, education programs, pilgrimages/tours, exhibitions, and annual and other organization meetings are among the subjects of the material.
    - Manuscripts and Publications, 213165 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Addresses Before the Horticultural Society, 1923, 1934; 213154 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 1)
      Includes "The Future of Nut Growing" (1923) by Robert T. Morris and "Shrubs" (1934) by Arthur Herrington.
    - Manuscript Poems, 1934-1935; 213156 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 2)
      Includes "Iussos Asperge Sapores" [about apple trees] sent by Mrs. H.C. Butler, from "Punch, and "I Have a Little Garden" by Benjamin Schloss.
    - A Five Foot Shelf of Garden Books, 1930s-1940s?; 213159 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 3)
      An annotated bibliography produced by the Hort's Library Committee.
    - Men Who Sought and Found by Ethel W. McCool, 1940s?; 213158 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 4)
      Compilation of articles on plant exploration written by McCool and originally published for the Hort's Bulletin.
    - Guide to English Gardens by Alice Chauncey, circa 1955; 213157 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 5)
      Two copies, both appear to be autographed by the author.
    - "Our Experiences with Orchid Plants in the Home" by Mrs. Thomas Powell, 1962; 213160 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 6)
      Includes takeaway notes for a course given at the Hort.
    - Information Bulletins, 1968-circa 1970; 213161 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 7)
      Includes articles on horticultural topics, including content for a House Plant Course.
    - Information Sheets, 1970s-1990s; 213245 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 8)
      Includes various forms of informational articles provided by the Hort on horticulture topics.
    - Miscellaneous Articles, circa 1970s-2000s; 213246 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 9)
      Includes a small number of tear sheets, clippings, brochures, and other documents on horticulture topics, but which do not appear to relate to Hort itself.
    - "A Horticultural Tour of Gardens Along the Beautiful Great Ouse", 2000; 213162 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 10)
      Includes the itinerary and related reading material for Hort's East Anglia tour, with Scott Appell.
    - "A Tour of the Floriade and Private and Public Gardens of the Netherlands", 2002; 213163 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 11)
      Includes reading material compiled by Hort Director Education Scott Appell.
    - Doing Time in the Garden: Life Lessons Through Prison Horticulture by James Jiler, 2006; 213164 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 12)
      Book is about Hort's GreenHouse and GreenTeam programs concerning vocational training at Rikers Island prison. The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F128 HV9306.N6 J55 2006.
    - Program Brochures & Pamphlets, 213166 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Program Calendars, 1933-1950; 213167 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 13)
    - Program Calendars, 1951-1969; 213168 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 14)
    - Program Calendars, 1968-1976; 213169 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 15)
    - Program Calendars, 1976-1979; 213170 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 16)
    - Program Calendars, 1980-1983; 213171 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 17)
    - Program Calendars, 1983-1989; 213172 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 18)
    - Program Calendars, 1990-1994; 213203 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 19)
    - Program Calendars, 1995-1997; 213204 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 20)
    - Program Calendars, 1997-2000; 213205 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 21)
    - Program Calendars, 2000-2006; 213206 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 22)
    - Compleat Gardener Lecture Calendars, 1987-1996; 213225 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 23)
    - Central Park Conservancy Program Calendars, 2002-2004; 213202 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 24)
      Includes programs offered in partnership with the Hort.
    - Forms, Invitations & Other Ephemera, 213247 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Early Ephemera, 1902, 1913, undated; 213251 (Offsite-box 87, Folder 1)
      Includes preliminary programs for the International Conference on Plant Breeding and Hybridization (1902) and a donation form (1913).
    - Scrapbook #1 (5 folders), 1917, 1921-circa 1944; 213252 (Offsite-box 87, Folder 2-6)
      Includes contents of a disbound scrapbook, including donation and membership forms, membership solicitation brochures, announcements of lectures, exhibitions and other programs, meeting announcements, etc.
    - Scrapbook #2 (16 folders), 1901-1951; 213334 (Offsite-box 87, Folder 7-22)
      Includes the contents of a disbound scrapbook that included certificates, organization constitution and by-laws (as amended over time), invitations, announcements, programs, brochures, admission tickets, and other ephemera related to flower shows, International Flower shows, conferences, pilgrimages, meetings, general organizational matters, various events, membership, etc.
    - Ephemera. General (18 folders), 1970-2010; 213389 (Offsite-box 88, Folder 1-18)
    - Ephemera. Membership, 1930s-2000s; 213579 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera. Library Benefits, 1994-2004; 213580 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 2)
    - Ephemera. Library General, 1990s-2000s?; 213581 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera. GreenWorks, 1988; 213582 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera. Stationery, undated; 213583 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera. Miscellaneous, 1980s-2000s?; 213584 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 6)
    - Press & Publicity, 213645 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Press Releases (2 folders), 1982-1986; 213585 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 7-8)
    - Program Updates, 1998-2002; 213586 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 9)
    - Press Kits, 1980s-2000s; 213587 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 10)
    - Publicity Press Book (Clippings, Disbound), 1986-1987; 213588 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1980-2005; 213589 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 12)
    - Posters & Proclamations, 213615 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Posters. Oversize, 1980-2000; 213617 (Drawer OS-Large)
      Includes Houseplant Societies Show "The Joy of Houseplants" (undated), blow-up of Hort advertisement in the New York Times (29 January 1980), New York Flower Shows (1985, 1987/art by Peter Max, 1990/art by Lorenz, 1992, 1995, 1996), Astor Place Flower Market (1982, designed by Susan Keiser), and New York is Book Country (2000, art by Robert Sabuda). There are multiple copies and versions of some of the posters.
    - Mayoral Proclamations (Flat box), 1986-1999; 213616 (Offsite-box 108, Folder 2)
      Includes "New York Flower Show Month" (1986 and 1987), "New York Flower Show Days" (1996), and "New York Horticultural Society Centennial Day" (1999) (1980s signed by Edward I. Koch, 1990s by Rudolph W. Giulani).
  - Subseries VI.C. Miscellaneous Print Material, 1811-1997; 212854; 7.25 Linear feet
    This subseries includes mid-nineteenth century horticultural publications from the American Institute of the City of New York, and even earlier items relating to the New York Horticultural Society (not be be confused with HSNY), the first such organization in the United States, founded in New York City in 1818. Also found here are visually-interesting seed catalogs from the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, and various loose botanical prints and engravings.
    The material in this subseries is sorted alphabetically by title or subject.
    - American Institute: Adoniram Chandler, Address, Delivered at the Close of the Nineteenth Annual Fair of the American Institute, of the City of New-York, at Castle Garden, October 23, 1846 (New York: Van Norden & Amerman, 1846)., 212999 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 1)
    - American Institute: Thomas Bridgeman, Horticultural Report of the Nineteenth Annual Fair of the American Institute, Held at Castle Garden, in the City of New-York, October, 1846 (New York: Van Gelder & Riley, 1846), 213000 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 2)
    - American Institute: Thomas Bridgeman and Peter B. Mead, Horticultural Report of the Twenty-First Annual Fair of the American Institute, Held at Castle Garden, New York City, October 1848 (New York: Joseph H. Jennings, 1848)., 213001 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 3)
    - American Institute: H. Meigs, Address Delivered at the Opening of the Twenty-Second Annual Fair of the American Institute at Castle Garden, October, 1849 (New York: William E. Dean, 1849)., 213003 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 4)
    - American Institute: Proceedings of the Second Congress of Fruit Growers, Convened Under the Auspices of the American Institute, in the City of New-York, 1849 (Albany: Charles Van Benthuysen, 1850)., 213005 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 5)
    - American Institute: Schedules of prizes, premiums, programs, etc., 1901-1903; 213006 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Botanical Artists, 2009 Directory of Members, 212947 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 7)
    - China--A Land of Beauty (Suzhou Gardens), 1960s-1970s; 212931 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 8)
    - Common Wild Flowers of New York State by Patricia Ellison, John M. Kingsbury, and Peter A. Hyypio (New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell University), [1975?]; 212928 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 9)
    - Eastern New York Horticultural Society: Fifth and Sixth Annual Meetings, 1901-1902; 212984 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 10)
      Appears to have been organized in 1896, Hudson River Valley area.
    - Elgin Botanic Garden: David Hosack, A Statement of Facts Relative to the Establishment and Progress of the Elgin Botanic Garden, and the Subsequent Disposal of the Same to the State of New-York (New York: C. S. Van Winkle, 1811)., 212989 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 11)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number Y1811 .Hos.
    - A Few Garden Pictures (New York: John Scheepers & Co., Inc., agents for R. Wallace & Co., Colchester, England), circa 1914; 212929 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 12)
    - Gourley, Josette (artist), circa 1983; 213146 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 13)
      Information about artist Josette Gourley, her painting "Carolina Swamp," and three notecard reproductions of her botanical illustrations.
    - Habit de Jardinier [reproduction antique French engraving], n.d.; 213193 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 14)
    - Hagan, Patti: gardening articles, 1984-1997; 212924 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 15)
      Photocopies of gardening articles by Patti Hagan from the New York Times and Wall Street Journal.
    - Home Landscapes (Westbury, N.Y.: Hicks Nurseries, Inc.), 1938; 212911 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 16)
    - Howard Studios Garden Ornaments. Catalogue No. 6., 1934; 212912 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 17)
    - Journal of Therapeutic Horticulture, vol. 5, 1990; 212946 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 18)
    - Martha Stewart Living, 1998 April; 212949 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 19)
    - The Mayflower [gardening periodical], 1897 April 18 & May 18; 212913 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 20)
    - Metropolitan Urban Garden Festival, April 23-26, 1998, Metro Tech Center, Downtown Brooklyn [flier], 213147 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 21)
    - Newport in Flower: A History of Newport's Horticultural Heritage by Harriet Jackson Phelps [draft], 1978; 212952 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 22)
      Typescript draft of Phelps's work, published in 1979. Includes correspondence regarding the foreword supplied by Charles D. Webster of the Horticultural Society of New York.
    - New York Florists' Club: Essays and Lectures, 1895, 1901, 1904; 212903 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 1)
    - New York Florists' Club: Publications, 1928-1972; 212905 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 2)
    - New York Florists' Club: Fiftieth Anniversary of the New York Florists' Club, 1887-1937 [souvenir journal], 212906 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 3)
    - New York Horticultural Society: Constitution and By-Laws of the New-York Horticultural Society, Incorporated March 22, 1822 (New York: J. Seymour, 1824), 213138 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 4)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F126 SB1 .N47 1824.
    - New York Horticultural Society: David Hosack, An Inaugural Discourse, Delivered Before the New-York Horticultural Society at Their Anniversary Meeting, on the 31st of August, 1824 (New York: J. Seymour, 1824)., 213139 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 5)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F126 S93 Box 1.
    - New York Horticultural Society: John Frederick Schroeder, Intellectual and Moral Resources of Horticulture. An Anniversary Discourse, Pronounced Before the New-York Horticultural Society, at the Annual Celebration, August 26, 1828 (New York: the Society, 1828), 213140 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 6)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number Pamph SB105 .S38 1838.
    - New York Horticultural Society: John W. Francis, An Address Delivered Before the New-York Horticultural Society, at Their Anniversary, on the Eighth of September, 1829 (New York: E. Conrad, 1830), 213141 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 7)
    - New York Horticultural Society: Monthly Report, 1881-1882; 213142 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 8)
      1881: September, October, November, December
      1882: February, March, April, May, September, November
      The N-YHS Library holds six issues from 1885 (February, March, April, May, November, December) under call number F126 SB1.N47 R4.
    - New York Horticultural Society: Illustrations from Frank Leslie's Illsutrated Newspaper, 1856, 1886; 213145 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 9)
      1856 July 5: "Exhibition of the N. Y. Horticultural Society at Clinton Hall, N. Y." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 5 July 1856 [photocopy; for original, see Box: FF-11, Folder 13]
      1886 November 13: "New York City.--The Eighth Annual Chrysanthemum Exhibition, Under the Auspices of the New York Horticultural Society, at Cosmopolitan Hall, Forty-First Street and Broadway, November 2D-6th."
    - Orchids in the Life and Culture of the Chinese People by Shiu-Ying Hu (Hong Kong: Chung Chi College), 1971; 212935 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 10)
    - [Prince] Linnaean Botanic Garden and Nurseries (Flushing, N.Y.: William Prince & Co.): broadside circulars and bill-of-sale, 1826-1878; 212986 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 11)
    - Roses by Bobbink & Atkins, 1927; 212926 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 12)
    - Roses of Yesterday (Watsonville, Ca.: Lester Rose Gardens), 1948; 212925 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 13)
    - Schermerhorn, Richard Jr.: Country Places of Old New York [research paper], n.d.; 213149 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 14)
    - Seed Catalog (Allen): 1870. Retail Priced Catalogue of Vegetable, Flower, Fruit, Herb and Field Seeds for Sale by R. H. Allen & Co. at Their Agricultural Implement & Seed Warehouses, 189 and 191 Water Street, New-York., 212907 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 15)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1884, 1888; 212882 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 1)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1895, 1897; 212884 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 2)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual + Unique List of the Best Seeds That Grow (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1898; 212886 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 3)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (2 copies) (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1901; 212888 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 4)